# ANDRE SARIZAL PUTRA

082285020082 I andre.sarizal.putra@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/andre-sarizal-putra I Depok

#### **About Me**

I am a fast-acting and dedicated professional with over 7 years of experience in data center technical support. I have extensive experience in maintaining data center infrastructure and developing web-based applications. One of my notable achievements is the development of a unique monitoring application that successfully analyzed the power consumption of data center infrastructure. This innovative solution not only reduced power usage but also resulted in an 18% cost savings. Recently, I completed a data analysis program at the Revou faculty, where I honed my skills in Python, SQL, Spreadsheets, and Tableau. With my experience in data center infrastructure and programming, as well as my newly enhanced analytical skills, I am confident that I can manage automated data from multiple tool sources and provide effective insights to improve decision making in any organization

#### **Skills**

**Technical Skills**: Data Cleaning, Statistic Analysis, Data Visualization, A/B Testing, Network, IT Infrastructure **Soft Skills**: Analytical Thinking, Problem-solving, Adaptability, Flexibility, Communication, Teamwork, Creative

Tools : Spreadsheet, Tableau, SQL, Python, Laravel (PHP Framework), JavaScript, API, SNMP

## **Working Experiences**

### **Datacenter Technical Support, Telkomsel**

February, 2017 – May, 2024

- Delivered efficient first-level technical support for network products and datacenter infrastructure, successfully resolving 15% of issues on the first contact, enhancing customer satisfaction and operational reliability.
- Proactively monitored the operational status of data center infrastructure, effectively preventing any fatal failures and ensuring consistent operations.
- Authored a detailed report on Power Usage Effectiveness and Data Center Infrastructure Efficiency (PUE DCiE), identifying key improvements that optimized energy consumption and achieved an 18% reduction in operational costs.
- Worked collaboratively with a team of facility operation professionals, playing a key role in the timely and successful completion of major Telkomsel projects, demonstrating strong teamwork and project management skills.

#### **Education**

## **Andalas University**

July, 2010 – November, 2016

Bachelor Degree of Information System

## Full-stack Data Analytics, RevoU Faculty

January, 2024 – May, 2024

Learn the process of cleaning, organizing, analyzing data to gain insights and visualize findings with impactful charts and graphs to communicate effectively

## **Project Experiences**

## Power System Monitoring, Full-stack Web Developers, Telkomsel

December, 2023 – May, 2024

- Created web-based applications in Telkomsel Telecommunication Center Buaran, monitoring power consumption, temperature and alarm on 28 rectifiers and 6 unit power supplies
- Improved system efficiency by 26.4%, resulting in significant cost savings and improved operational efficiency.
- Collaborated with a cross-functional team, contributing to the successful completion of the project within the stipulated time frame.

## Delivery Performance Analysis, Full-stack Data Analytics, Revou Faculty

May, 2024 – May, 2024

- Analyzed food delivery performance in Goeats Company, achieving a 47.6% forecasted reduction in delivery time during traffic jams by optimizing type of vehicle used, vehicle health and distance delivered.
- Identified and implemented strategies to improve delivery efficiency, resulting in a 21.7% forecasted increase in customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a team of operation professionals, contributing to the successful completion of Goeats projects within the stipulated time frames.

#### Certifications

#### Certification:

- 1. Certificate of appreciation to managed datacenter, Issued by Telkomsel
- November 10, 2022 April 05, 2024

- 2. Full-stack Data Analytics, Issued by Revou
- 3. SQL (Basic), Issued by Hacker Rank

February 14, 2024